<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[zalary.github.io]]></title>
  <link href="http://zalary.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zalary.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-10T15:05:33-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://zalary.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zalary Young]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[zalary+comments@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Colorful Cat]]></title>
    <link href="http://zalary.github.io/blog/2014/03/10/colorful-cat/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-10T13:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zalary.github.io/blog/2014/03/10/colorful-cat</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I learned a neat trick about using &lsquo;cat&rsquo; in the terminal to view a file from a <a href="http://themakersquare.com">MakerSquare</a> <a href="http://www.sethszymanski.com/2014/02/11/lolcat.html">classmate</a>, but I wondered, could it be better?</p>

<p>While not as entertaining as lolcat, I found
<a href="http://pygments.org/">Pygments</a> which is package for python, but
totally works in Mac OSX.  You can download and install it manually, or
use <a href="http://www.pip-installer.org/en/latest/">PIP</a> (which is just a pkg
manager for python).</p>

<p>Then, alias cat to &lsquo;pygmentize -g&rsquo; in your bashrc or zshrc file, and
voila, syntax-higlighted file viewing, direct from your terminal!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Makersquare Week 1, time says 'Woosh']]></title>
    <link href="http://zalary.github.io/blog/2014/02/10/makersquare-week-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T17:29:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://zalary.github.io/blog/2014/02/10/makersquare-week-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first week went by so quickly!  Somehow we&rsquo;re starting &ndash; as Harsh called it this morning &ndash; &lsquo;Season 4, Episode 2&rsquo; (Cohort 4, Week 2).</p>

<p>Truthfully last week I really struggled with the Ruby basics.  I have a general grasp of things I want to do and how I should do them, but my actual implementation needs refinement.  Fortunately I have a great friend who came over and walked through some of the projects with me.  And today, I&rsquo;m happy to report, my pair and I were able to get through all the exercises.  I was even able to get through the Extension exercise! :)</p>

<p>So here are my take-aways from the last week:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>TDD is the best thing ever.  If you use it right, it walks you through how to code the solution!</p></li>
<li><p>Watch your arrays vs hashes vs objects.</p>

<ul>
<li>When you don&rsquo;t write your own tests for TDD make sure you know what&rsquo;s being asked for.  So much frustration came from me returning the right idea but in the wrong way.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Frustration is part of the game, but don&rsquo;t give up.  Go for a walk or get away from the problem, but keep coming back and trying different stuff.  Even when I can&rsquo;t get there without help, I&rsquo;ve been so close, or I&rsquo;ve tried something so close to the right answer.  It&rsquo;s not encouraging in the moment, but it&rsquo;s nice when you come to the solution and can look back at your process and see how close you were.  Learn from that.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>With regards to practical newbie tips, here are my favorite 2.</p>

<p>When looping through a hash, you can call the key AND the value, like so</p>

<pre><code>inventory.each do |item|
    puts "There are #{item[:quantity]} #{item[:name]}(s) and they cost #{item[:price]} each."
    puts "the total cost of #{item[:name]} is   #{item[:price].to_f * item[:quantity]}"
   total += item[:price].to_f * item[:quantity]
   puts total
end
</code></pre>

<p>One of those things that seems obvious in retrospect, but gave me so much trouble.</p>

<p>The other neat thing I learned was stubbing time for an rspec test.  For instance, if you want to make sure your script is going to return &lsquo;late&rsquo; after a given time, you can write your test like</p>

<pre><code> it 'should show late if past 30 min' do
  thing = Thing.new
  @time_now = Time.parse("Feb 11 2014")
  Time.stub(:now).and_return(@time_now)
  expect(thing.late?).to eq(true)
end    
</code></pre>

<p>et voila!</p>

<p>So much magic to learn, so little time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MakerSquare Day 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://zalary.github.io/blog/2014/02/04/makersquare-day-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-04T20:38:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://zalary.github.io/blog/2014/02/04/makersquare-day-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Day 1 of Makersquare: fun, exciting, challenging, overwhelming!</p>

<p>There was a lot of stuff! Figuring out the vibe, introduction to the
course &ndash; there were past cohort instructors and students to spill all,
setting up our dev environment and then diving right into code. Lots of
ruby review which is still my weakest chop.</p>

<p>I have a few exercise to finish tonight, and a few I really want to
review again, but I&rsquo;m feeling confident that even things I suck at seem
to be gelling a bit more. Bring on day 2!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MakerSquare, 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://zalary.github.io/blog/2013/12/19/makersquare/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-19T14:36:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://zalary.github.io/blog/2013/12/19/makersquare</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As the title might imply, I&rsquo;ve been accepted into the
<a href="http://themakersquare.com/" title="">MakerSquare</a> Spring Cohort. As the kids
might say, &ldquo;ALL THE FEELS!&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Open Letter to the Angular Conference Organizers]]></title>
    <link href="http://zalary.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/an-open-letter-to-the-angular-conference-organizers/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-17T10:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zalary.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/an-open-letter-to-the-angular-conference-organizers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, <a href="http://www.ng-conf.org/" title="ng-conf">ng-conf</a> tickets went on sale, then sold out immediately.  A co-worker forwarded me the email about the next round of tickets, and the email also mentioned the &lsquo;girl-ticket&rsquo; option.  You can read the email <a href="http://us7.campaign-archive1.com/?u=e45fd510f70a16fd9f7797276&amp;id=2b2ad4dddd&amp;e=8d815c38e3" title="More Tickets &amp; Girl Tickets">here</a>.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s my response:</p>

<blockquote><p>Hi there,</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m a female, and while I would love to come to your conference, the girl-ticket, pink lanyard situation leaves a bad taste in my mouth.</p>

<p>I feel like the underlying intention is right, but the execution just seems misguided.</p>

<p>On one hand, I would love to be able to skip the line and be assured a spot at this conference at a somewhat discounted price.  However, as a <em>woman</em> in tech, I&rsquo;ve worked hard to prove myself equal and deserving and I can certainly wait in line with all the &lsquo;boys&rsquo; and get a ticket in the same way they do.</p>

<p>Further, the pink lanyard seems like a slap in the face, both to anyone wearing one and to anyone else (man, woman, trans-gendered, etc) who wants to get in and either has to pay more, or wait longer or knows someone who wanted to attend but couldn&rsquo;t due to ticket shortage (as it seems there is).</p>

<p>I would love to see the Angular community reach out to females in other ways.   Maybe through RailsGirls, or Girl Develop It (again, with the girls, but I do respect the mission) or even just reaching out to those of us already in the community.  Let it be known (on your front page, and not buried in an email) that you&rsquo;d love to see more diversity (gender, et al) at your conference and that you&rsquo;re committed to making it an encouraging and educational experience for everyone.  Then, do commit to it.</p>

<p>I want to acknowledge that I come from a place of privilege.  I work with a great bunch of guys who have never excluded me or downplayed my abilities.  I have a boss who encourages my training and conference attendance.  I haven&rsquo;t been harassed or made to feel unwelcome at any conference I&rsquo;ve attended &ndash; and I&rsquo;m grateful for all of that.</p>

<p>My hope is that eventually every woman/girl in tech has that same experience, of being exactly what she is &ndash; equal and deserving of her place &ndash; even if she has to stand in line to be there.</p>

<p>Crossing my parts for the second round of early-bird tickets,</p>

<p>Zalary Young
@zalary</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chapter 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://zalary.github.io/blog/2013/04/18/chapter-4/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-18T21:20:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zalary.github.io/blog/2013/04/18/chapter-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I made it through <a href="http://ruby.railstutorial.org/chapters/rails-flavored-ruby#top">Chapter4</a> of the Rails Tutorial tonight.  Everything was pretty nice until the last example in the last exercise didn&rsquo;t execute the way it should.</p>

<p>It took a little banging my head into the wall until I remembered something mentioned earlier, and realized I was somehow running 1.8.7 and not 1.9.3 like I thought. So first I went and looked back at how to make the code work in 1.8.7 and &lsquo;finished&rsquo; the exercise.</p>

<p>Then I decided figure out why rbenv was supposedly installed but wasn&rsquo;t doing what I expected.   There was a little flailing, but I googled around and poked some and finally got it figured it out and fixed.</p>

<p>The lessons I learn sometimes are not the ones I expect, but they keep me moving forward.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[vim goodness]]></title>
    <link href="http://zalary.github.io/blog/2013/04/15/vim-goodness/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-15T22:21:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zalary.github.io/blog/2013/04/15/vim-goodness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While getting back into code, I am also getting into vim. When I used it previously, I pretty much knew &lsquo;i&rsquo;, which just leads to a lot of frustration.  This time, since I&rsquo;m coding mostly via ssh to my ubunu vm, I&rsquo;m much more reliant on the terminal for navigating and coding, so I&rsquo;m taking the time to learn the myriad of keyboard commands that make vim rock.</p>

<p>And now that I&rsquo;ve installed pathogen and figured out where to put/adjust things, I can piddle even more!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m just scratching the surface at this point, but even so, I can see how it&rsquo;s a total game-changer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get back to it]]></title>
    <link href="http://zalary.github.io/blog/2013/04/14/get-back-to-it/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-14T15:07:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zalary.github.io/blog/2013/04/14/get-back-to-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong> This is a test </strong></p>

<ul>
<li>New house</li>
<li>Standing desk</li>
<li>Opportunity</li>
</ul>


<p>That just leaves the following</p>

<ul>
<li>Code daily</li>
<li>Blog about it</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
